[{"question": "where was george washington born", "answer": "westmoreland country virginia va"}, {"question": "who was benjamin franklin", "answer": "benny boy"}, {"question": "who was thomas jefferson", "answer": "tommy boy"}, {"question": "Which statement about a wave produced by a doorbell is true?", "answer": "It propagates in the form of compression and rarefactions"}, {"question": "What is the term for producing a current by changing a ", "answer": "magnetic induction"}, {"question": "What aspect of culture does the following excerpt from \"What For\" by Garrett Hongo celebrate?", "answer": "family"}, {"question": "What happens if you move a magnet near a coil of wire?", "answer": "Current is induced."}, {"question": "Which item, when wrapped with a current-carrying coil, produces the greatest magnetic field inside the coil?", "answer": "iron rod"}, {"question": "What happens to the electric current if the number of loops of a wire doubles?", "answer": "It doubles."}, {"question": "A turbine is an example of which of the following?", "answer": "generator"}, {"question": "What do slinky waves and seismic waves have in common?", "answer": "Both are mechanical waves."}, {"question": "Sound waves are mechanical waves. Which statement is true for this type of wave?", "answer": "Sound waves require a medium in order to transport energy."}, {"question": "What is the distance from the crest to the equilibrium of a wave called?", "answer": "amplitude"}, {"question": "What does the trough of a wave refer to?", "answer": "the lowest point of the wave"}, {"question": "A pure sound wave, generated by a tuning fork, is considered a periodic wave. Which statement is true for this tuning fork sound wave?", "answer": "Every wave has the same wave pattern."}, {"question": "The frequency of the musical note F#3 is 1.85 \u00d7 102 hertz. What is its period?", "answer": "5.40 \u00d7 10-3 seconds"}, {"question": "The frequency of a wave traveling through the air of a hot, dry desert is 1,200 hertz. Its wavelength is 0.300 meters. What is the speed of the wave?", "answer": "360 meters/second"}, {"question": "If the tension in a rope is increased, what will happen to the speed of a wave traveling through the rope?", "answer": "The speed will increase."}, {"question": "A water wave has a speed of 23.0 meters/second. If the wave\u2019s frequency is 0.0680 hertz, what is the wavelength?", "answer": "338 meters"}, {"question": "Lightwaves travel from the air into a lens made of glass. Their velocity decreases as they enter the glass. How does this affect the frequency and wavelength of the lightwaves?", "answer": "Their frequency stays the same and their wavelength decreases."}, {"question": "In a harbor, you can see sea waves traveling around the edges of small stationary boats. Why does this happen?", "answer": "diffraction"}, {"question": "Which statement is true about how objects appear to bend that are partially submerged in water?", "answer": "They appear to bend at the surface due to refraction."}, {"question": "Kevin is standing outside a railway station. He can know whether a train is approaching the station or departing from the sound it makes. Which principle of sound waves is he using?", "answer": "Doppler effect"}, {"question": "What do we get when two sound waves of slightly different frequencies interfere with each other?", "answer": "beats"}, {"question": "When does resonance occur?", "answer": "when the frequency of a forced vibration equals the natural frequency"}, {"question": "Which statement best explains that sound waves are pressure waves?", "answer": "Sound waves have regions of compressions and rarefactions."}, {"question": "What is the speed of sound at the atmospheric temperature of 30\u00b0C?", "answer": "349 meters/second"}, {"question": "How will the speed of a sound wave change if the temperature of the medium rises?", "answer": "The speed will increase."}, {"question": "Which statement is true about the loudness of sound?", "answer": "It is inversely proportional to the square of the distance of the listener from the source."}, {"question": "Two sound waves traveling in the same medium interfere with each other. The compression of one wave falls on the compression of the other wave. What can you say about the resultant sound?", "answer": "The resultant sound will be louder than the individual sound waves."}, {"question": "Which property of the sound wave undergoes a change with an increase in its energy?", "answer": "amplitude"}, {"question": "If the pitch of the sound coming out from a speaker increases, which is true about the sound wave?", "answer": "wavelength decreases"}, {"question": "For a while, Southern Brewers is the only coffee supplier in the market. Eventually, Albert Coffee enters the market and sells coffee at lower prices than Southern Brewers does. Later, Caf\u00e9 Brites enters the same market with lower prices for coffee. Southern Brewers now charges lower prices than Albert Coffee and Caf\u00e9 Brites do. What made Southern Brewers lower its prices?", "answer": "competition"}, {"question": "In a certain economy, people save some part of their income in the financial sector and use the remaining part for consumption. The government decides to increase the tax rates for everyone in that economy. What effect will the tax increase have on savings and investment in the economy?", "answer": "Savings decrease, and investment decreases."}, {"question": "Mia and Jack are two chocolate producers. Mia packs her chocolates in attractive boxes and charges slightly more than Jack does. Despite her slightly higher prices, consumers are more attracted to Mia\u2019s chocolates. What market structure does this situation represent?", "answer": "monopolistic competition"}, {"question": "The graph represents price and output quantities under a monopoly. What price will the monopolist firm set?", "answer": "$15"}, {"question": "What is marginal cost?", "answer": "It is the change in a company\u2019s total cost arising from a change in total output of one unit."}, {"question": "Which statement defines equilibrium in a graph showing demand and supply curves?", "answer": "It is the point where the demand and supply curves intersect."}, {"question": "Which statements are true according to the law of demand?", "answer": "A decrease in price leads to an increase in quantity demanded."}, {"question": "Which statement defines externality?", "answer": "It is the impact of production and consumption on unrelated third parties."}, {"question": "Jack put his jeans in the washing machine to do his laundry. He forgot to remove a $10 bill from his pocket. When he removed his pants from the washing machine, the money wasn\u2019t torn. All he has to do now is dry the bill so he can use it again. Which characteristic of money does Jack\u2019s situation demonstrate?", "answer": "durability"}, {"question": "What is a federal budget?", "answer": "an estimate of the government\u2019s total revenue and spending"}, {"question": "Recently, the government noticed that the consumption of cigarettes has increased among working individuals. To counter this increase, the government decides to raise the cost of cigarettes by increasing the excise tax on them. After six months, the government observes that the consumption of cigarettes has decreased to some extent. Which type of taxation did the government use?", "answer": "indirect tax"}, {"question": "Which of the following is an indicator of economic growth?", "answer": "gross domestic product"}, {"question": "Under which type of policy does the government reduce its expenditures and increase tax rates?", "answer": "contractionary fiscal policy"}, {"question": "What is the direction of the magnetic field lines outside any magnet?", "answer": "from north to south"}, {"question": "What is the force that can cause two pieces of iron to attract each other?", "answer": "['magnetic force']"}, {"question": "What are the opposite ends of a magnet called?", "answer": "['north and south poles']"}, {"question": "Which action will cause the magnetic force to push two magnets closer together?", "answer": "['aligning the north pole and south pole of different magnets']"}, {"question": "This diagram of the first right-hand rule relates which two quantities?", "answer": "['current (thumb) to magnetic field (fingers)']"}, {"question": "Where are the magnetic fields strongest near a bar magnet?", "answer": "['ends']"}, {"question": "What generates the magnetic field in a current carrying wire?", "answer": "['movement of charged particles']"}, {"question": "A negative charge is moving across a room from south to north. A magnetic field runs from east to west. In what direction is the magnetic force on the moving negative charge?", "answer": "['toward the floor']"}, {"question": "The path of an electron, traveling at 3.7 \u00d7 104 meters/second, is making a right angle to a magnetic field. A single electron experiences a force of 2.2 \u00d7 10-15 newtons while in the field. What is the strength of the magnetic field? The value of q = -1.6 \u00d7 10-19 coulombs.", "answer": "['0.37 teslas']"}, {"question": "If the EMF produced in a wire is 0.88 volts and the wire moves perpendicular to a magnetic field of strength 0.075 newtons/amp\u00b7meter at a speed of 4.20 meters/second, what is the length of the wire in the magnetic field?", "answer": "['2.8 meters']"}, {"question": "A wire that is 0.86 meters long is moved perpendicularly through a constant magnetic field of strength 0.035 newtons/amp\u00b7meter at a speed of 6.0 meters/second. What is the emf produced?", "answer": "['0.18 volts']"}, {"question": "Which of the following factors could you change in a system and not change its induced EMF?", "answer": "['type of wire']"}, {"question": "Which device transforms electrical energy to mechanical energy?", "answer": "['motor']"}, {"question": "What shape can be drawn though a solenoid to determine the magnitude of its magnetic field?", "answer": "['rectangle']"}, {"question": "Which law represents an induced electric current?", "answer": "['Faraday\u2019s Law']"}, {"question": "What were Gorbechev\u2019s economic reform efforts called?", "answer": "['perestroika']"}, {"question": "Which group of anti-Soviets did the U.S. support in Afghanistan?", "answer": "['Mujahadeen']"}, {"question": "Which was a fundamental element of supply-side economics?", "answer": "['economic deregulation']"}, {"question": "Who led the Solidarity movement in Poland?", "answer": "['Lech Walesa']"}, {"question": "In which country did President George H.W. Bush's diplomatic skills result in a foreign policy that demonstrates the power of multilateralism?", "answer": "['Iraq']"}, {"question": "What was a criticism made of George H.W. Bush's New World Order?", "answer": "['It was vague and its parameters were hard to define.']"}, {"question": "Imagine you are a candidate for president. Your campaign manager tells you that Social Security reform is the \u201cthird rail of politics\u201d and is considered an issue to be avoided. Why would your campaign manager give you this advice?", "answer": "['The program is popular with seniors, who vote more often than other groups.']"}, {"question": "For what purpose was the Environmental Protection Agency established?", "answer": "['to oversee guidelines for clean water, air, and other environmental issues']"}, {"question": "What is the primary purpose of the Kyoto Protocol?", "answer": "['to limit and decrease the worldwide emission of greenhouse gases']"}, {"question": "Which best describes conservation, as it applies to environmentalism?", "answer": "['the preservation and protection of land and other natural resources for enjoyment by future generations']"}, {"question": "Frederick Taylor is known best for what concept that improves efficiency in manufacturing?", "answer": "['time-study analysis']"}, {"question": "Which of the following products is petroleum based?", "answer": "['plastic']"}, {"question": "The effect of Sputnik 1 could best be described in which of the following ways?", "answer": "['leading to technological innovation and communication with satellites']"}, {"question": "Time-study analysis could best be summarized by which of the following descriptions?", "answer": "['a method of labor management to improve overall efficiency']"}, {"question": "Which situation would create a field like the one shown here?", "answer": "['an interaction between a magnetic south pole and a north pole']"}, {"question": "Why is a magnetic field a vector quantity?", "answer": "['directional force']"}, {"question": "How are magnetic poles and electrical charges similar?", "answer": "['Their same forces repel each other, and their opposite forces attract each other.']"}, {"question": "When is the magnetic field the strongest?", "answer": "['when the field lines are close together']"}, {"question": "A proton travels at right angles through a magnetic field of 0.025 teslas.", "answer": "['4.5 \u00d7 106 meters/ second']"}, {"question": "One beam of electrons moves at right angles to a magnetic field.", "answer": "['(4.9 \u00d7 10-14 newtons) \u00b7 sin(30\u00b0)']"}, {"question": "A positive charge is moving from the floor of a room toward the ceiling.", "answer": "['toward the south']"}, {"question": "What is the magnetic force acting on an electron if its speed is 3.0 \u00d7 10", "answer": "['F = -9.6 \u00d7 10-15 newtons']"}, {"question": "What is the difference between the fields surrounding a stationary charge and those that surround a moving charge?", "answer": "['A moving charge has both an electric and magnetic field and a stationary charge has only an electric field.']"}, {"question": "What is the emf produced in a 1.5 meter wire moving at a speed of 6.2 meters/second perpendicular to a magnetic field of strength 3.96 \u00d7 10-3 newtons/amp\u00b7meter ?", "answer": "['0.037 volts']"}, {"question": "Complete the following sentence about the effects of economic globalization.", "answer": "['cost', 'producers']"}, {"question": "Wartime challenges caused the government to take an active role in the economy; what steps did the government NOT take?", "answer": "['Unmarried women were required to work in factories.']"}, {"question": "What is not true about the War Production Board (WPB)?", "answer": "['FDR created the WPB and was the first director of the board.']"}, {"question": "What was true about African Americans in the military?", "answer": "['Most African Americans were deployed to support roles.']"}, {"question": "What group of women was initially targeted to join the labor force?", "answer": "['young unmarried women']"}, {"question": "What organization was not created during the war years?", "answer": "['TVA']"}, {"question": "Which phenomenon occurs when light falls on a smooth mirror?Which phenomenon occurs when light falls on a smooth mirror? ", "answer": "['specular reflection']"}, {"question": "A ray of light is traveling from water into a diamond.A ray of light is traveling from water into a diamond.Upon hitting the diamond, a light ray bends toward the normal.With this information, what can you say about the speed of light as it passes from water into a diamond?", "answer": "['The speed decreases.']"}, {"question": "Which statement about the spectrum of light that emerges from a prism is true?", "answer": "['High-frequency colors bend more than low-frequency colors.']"}, {"question": "What is the critical angle of a diamond having a refractive index of 2.42?What is the critical angle of a diamond having a refractive index of 2.42?Use air as the second medium.Air has the refractive index 1.00.", "answer": "['24.4\u00b0']"}, {"question": "What is the refractive index of a solution that has a critical angle of 40.8\u00b0 with respect to air?What is the refractive index of a solution that has a critical angle of 40.8\u00b0 with respect to air?The refracting index of air is 1.00.", "answer": "['1.53']"}, {"question": "Dan confirms the authenticity of an amethyst stone by a few tests.Dan confirms the authenticity of an amethyst stone by a few tests.During one of the tests, he finds the angle of the refracted ray of light coming out of the amethyst into the air as 28\u00b0.If the refractive index of amethyst is 1.55, what is the incident angle?", "answer": "['47\u00b0']"}, {"question": "What is a necessary condition for total internal reflection in a medium?", "answer": "['when the angle of incidence is greater than the critical angle']"}, {"question": "The refractive index of water is greater than that of air but is less than that of glass or a diamond.The refractive index of water is greater than that of air but is less than that of glass or a diamond.Under which condition can there be total internal reflection in water?", "answer": "['when light travels from water to air']"}, {"question": "Which statement is true of a glass lens that diverges light in air?", "answer": "['It is thin near the center and thick at the edges.']"}, {"question": "What happens to a light ray passing through the center of a lens?", "answer": "['It passes without any deviation.']"}, {"question": "What determines the type of the image formed after refraction from a convex lens?", "answer": "['position of the object']"}, {"question": "What happens to parallel light rays that strike a concave lens?", "answer": "['They diverge on refraction.']"}, {"question": "At what distance from a convex lens must an object be to get a virtual image?", "answer": "['at a distance less than the focal length']"}]